

Hilla Klemetti Designer

+358 50 320 2039

hilla.klemetti@aalto.fi

hillaklemetti.me

Linkedin k

Information Networks student at Aalto University - majoring in User, Data & Design

I enjoy ideation, problem solving and teamwork. I want to be designing better services, societies and ways of living. For that it's crucial to understand the role of technology in today's society. I'm into socially and environmentally driven entrepreneurship, that I researched in my bachelor's thesis on the Innovation Potential of Startup Businesses Targeting the Sustainable Development Goals on Equality.

Experience

Self Employed

Mar 2019 - today

Personal Company

Through self employment, I've done concept design, website design, search engine optimisation, marketing, photography, videography, B2B customer survey reporting and translations.

Board Member &

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Coordinator

Aalto Entrepreneurship Society

My responsibilties included project coordination, communications and community building. I was also involved in project ideation, event organisation and podcast hosting to name a few.

Co-founder & Designer

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

Wicked Helsinki

I was part of the founding team of an impact entrepreneurship community Wicked Helsinki. I was responsible for designing the brand identity, hosting meet-ups and other project management tasks

Sales & Marketing Aug 2016 - Sep 2020

Detalji boutique

I was responsible for sales, digital content creation, social media marketing and the newsletter. I also planned and executed styling, photoshoots and filming.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Technology – graduated with honours

Aalto University 2018-2022

Exchange semester

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (Mexico)

Spring 2022

Ylioppilas

Oulunkylän yhteiskoulu 2014–2018

Exchange year

Lycée Jacques Prévert (France) 2015-2016

Skills

Service design
Concept design
Data gathering
Data analysis
Prototyping
Problem solving
Project management
Communications
Community building

Finnish, English, French, Spanish, Swedish

Tools

Miro Figma Adobe Softwares HTML, CSS, Scala Data analytics with R Atlas.ti SPSS

References

Nina Pyykönen owner of Detalji boutique +358 40 513 7383

Mona Ismail president of Aaltoes 2021 +358 45 206 9025